Guide to the Don Schmidt Collection of NC State Athletics Memorabilia
Don Schmidt Collection of NC State Athletics Memorabilia
1975-2000
Schmidt Don
MC 00462
The Don Schmidt Collection of NC State Athletics Memorabilia includes rugs, newspaper clippings, magazines, bumper stickers, basketball cards, keychains, buttons and pins, media guides, and other artifacts related to the history of NC State Athletics, primarily the Men's Basketball program. Materials range in date from 1975 to 2000.
Don Schmidt is an NC State alumnus and employee in Outreach, Communications, & Consulting. He and his family have collected NC State athletics memorabilia since the 1970s.
6.325 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Gift of Don Schmidt, 2012 (Accession 2012.0248)
This collection has not yet received full archival processing. Materials are arranged in the order received.
Don Schmidt is an NC State employee in Outreach, Communications, Consulting. He and his family have collected NC State athletics memorabilia since the 1970s.
The Don Schmidt Collection of NC State Athletics Memorabilia includes rugs, newspaper clippings, magazines, bumper stickers, basketball cards, keychains, buttons and pins, media guides, and other artifacts related to the history of NC State Athletics, primarily the Men's Basketball program. Materials range in date from 1975 to 2000.
Schmidt Don; North Carolina State University--History; North Carolina State University--Sports--History; North Carolina State University--Basketball; North Carolina State University--Mascots; North Carolina State University Athletics; North Carolina Athletics; North Carolina Basketball; Memorabilia; North Carolina History College sports
- Handmade rug featuring Wolf mascot, undated (Carton 1)
- "Wolfpack Tracks" record with a note and autograph from Wally Ausley, 1983 (Carton 1)
- Official NC State leaf bag, undated (Carton 1)
- Rally towel, reads "Go Pack!", undated (Carton 1)
- Newspaper clippings regarding Jim Valvano, circa 1993 (Carton 1)
- Rug, reads "This is Wolfpack Country, North Carolina State University", undated (Carton 1)
- Cotton throw blanket, reads "NC State University Wolfpack" with Wolf mascot, circa 1990s (Carton 1)
- Bumper stickers, 1983, 1990s (Carton 1)
- Basketball cards, 1987-1991 (Cardbox 2)
- Wolfpack notepads, undated (Cardbox 3)
- Basketball cards, 1999-2000 (Cardbox 3)
- NC State keychains, undated (Cardbox 3)
- Ceramic Wolf mascot, undated (Cardbox 3)
- Mug, reads "N.C. State Wolfpack, National Champions, '83" with a basketball going through a net, 1983 (Cardbox 3)
- Magazines and newspaper clippings pertaining to Wolfpack athletics, 1975-1999 (Halfbox 4)
- Statuette of an NC State player shooting a basketball at a goal post (small), undated (Box 5)
- Statuette of an NC State player shooting a basketball at a goal post (large), undated (Box 5)
- Poster, reads "N.C.S.U. Wolfpack" with Wolf wearing a football uniform, undated (Flatfolder 6)
- NC State keychains, 1983, undated (Carton 7)
- Wolfpack pins/buttons, undated (Carton 7)
- Wolfpack pens and pencils, undated (Carton 7)
- NC State decals/bumper stickers, undated (Carton 7)
- Wolf mascot magnet, undated (Carton 7)
- Headbands, read "NCSU" and "N.C. State", undated (Carton 7)
- NC State shoelace, undated (Carton 7)
- ACC Basketball Tournament Champions Collections Cards, limited edition 40 card set, 1992 (Carton 7)
- "Wolfpack Blend" ground coffee, undated (Carton 7)
- Canister, reads "N.C. State Wolfpack", 1992 (Carton 7)
- Rally towels, read "Wolfpack, Just Do It", undated (Carton 7)
- Basketball with Wolf's head and "Wolfpack," autographed by the 1990-1991 Men's Basketball Team, circa 1990 - circa 1991 (Carton 7)
- Plaque with Wolf mascot, reads "N.C. State, Wolfpack" with plate that reads "Gary Dornburg" underneath, undated (Carton 7)
- Trophy with plate that reads "North Carolina State University, 1990-1991" (Carton 7)
- Cassette tapes (2) entitled "The Cardiac Kids," narrated by Wally Ausley with his autograph, 1983 (Carton 7)
  Use copies must be made prior to patron use.
- Men's basketball cards, 1982, circa 1989, 1990-1991, 1991-1992 (Cardbox 8)
  Some cards are autographed.
- Wolfpack playing cards, undated (Cardbox 8)
- NC State Basketball Media Guide, 1989-1990 (Halfbox 9)
- NC State Basketball Media Guide, 1991-1992 (Halfbox 9)
- NC State Basketball Media Guide, 1992-1993 (Halfbox 9)
- NC State Basketball Program: Duke (February 21, 1990) - Wake Forest (March 4, 1990) (Halfbox 9)
  Cover reads "Wally Ausley, 30 Years 'The Voice of the Wolfpack,'" and is autographed by Ausley.
- NC State Football Media Guide, 1989 (Halfbox 9)
- Basketball autographed by Jim Valvano, circa 1980 - circa 1990 (Carton 10)